Usage: copilot login [options]

Authenticate with Copilot via OAuth device flow.

The default authentication mode is a web-based browser flow. After completion,
an authentication token will be stored securely in the system credential store.
If a credential store is not found or there is an issue using it, the token will
be stored in a plain text config file under ~/.copilot/.

Alternatively, Copilot CLI will use an authentication token found in environment
variables. This method is most suitable for "headless" use such as automation.
The following are checked in order of precedence: COPILOT_GITHUB_TOKEN,
GH_TOKEN,
GITHUB_TOKEN. See `copilot help environment` for more info.

Supported token types include fine-grained personal access tokens (v2 PATs) with
the "Copilot Requests" permission, OAuth tokens from the GitHub Copilot CLI app,
and OAuth tokens from the GitHub CLI (gh) app.

Classic personal access tokens (ghp_) are not supported.

Use --host to authenticate with a GitHub Enterprise Cloud instance that uses
data
residency (e.g., https://example.ghe.com).

Options:
  --config-dir <directory>  Set the configuration directory (default:
                            ~/.copilot)
  -h, --help                display help for command
  --host <host>             GitHub host URL (default: https://github.com)

Examples:
  # Authenticate with github.com
  $ copilot login

  # Authenticate with GitHub Enterprise Cloud (data residency)
  $ copilot login --host https://example.ghe.com

  # Use a fine-grained PAT via environment variable
  $ COPILOT_GITHUB_TOKEN=github_pat_... copilot

Learn More:
  Use `copilot <command> --help` for more information about a command.
  Read the documentation at https://docs.github.com/copilot/how-tos/copilot-cli
